Guide to the James Watson Webb Jr. Photographs 1930s PR 318
New-York Historical Society
James Watson Webb Jr. photographs
1930s
New-York Historical Society
Webb, J. Watson, Jr., 1916-2000
PR 318
0.5 Linear feet (1 box)
This collection contains 55 black and white photographs, primarily aerial shots of New York City in the 1930's. Some of the photos include cars of the era. There is also one color photograph of the photographer, James Watson Webb, Junior.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection contains 55 black and white photographs, primarily aerial shots of New York City in the 1930's. Buildings depicted include the Empire State Building, the Pierre Hotel, and the New York Public Library. Cars of the era are visible in some of the photographs. There are also several night views of Manhattan, and a color photograph of the photographer.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ursula M. Kammer Fox in memory of James Watson Webb, Jr., 2008.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Biographical Note
James Watson Webb III (known as James, Jr.) (1916-2000) was an American film editor and heir to the Havemeyer and Vanderbilt families.
Born in New York City, Webb was educated at Yale and moved to Hollywood, rising to head the editing department at 20th Century Fox. In 1960, he succeeded his mother, Electra Havemyer Webb, as President of the Shelburne Museum. Electra Havemyer Webb founded the Shelburne Museum in 1947 to house her own large collection of American folk art.
Bridges -- New York (State) -- New York -- Aerial photographs.; Buildings -- New York (State) -- New York -- Photographs.; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.) -- Aerial photographs.; New York (N.Y.) -- Aerial photographs.; Black-and-white photographs.; Color photographs.; Webb, J. Watson, Jr., 1916-2000 -- Portraits.
- Aerial views, "canyon" shots showing streets and cars (6), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Aerial view showing Penn Station (1), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Aerial views around Central Park (4), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Aerial views of midtown buildings, including Empire State Building and Pierre Hotel (4), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Aerial view with Bayonne Bridge (1), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Aerial views with Queensboro Bridge (5), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Shots of bridge spans (George Washington Bridge and Golden Gate bridge) (5) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Shots of ship masts (5), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Close-up shots of buildings (including Rockefeller Center and Empire State Building) (11), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Close-up shots of buildings, including New York Public Library (6), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Night views (7), 1930's (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photograph of James Watson Webb, Jr., circa 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)